<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Clémence FALIGOT</title><link>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Clémence FALIGOT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 08:15:16 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aphorya</title><link>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/aphorya/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 08:15:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/aphorya/</guid><description>Subject Aphorya is a social network project currently under development. Once completed, it will allow players to have a place where they can meet and plan their games. The goal is to bring players together and allow them to easily find gaming groups.
Problem How do you develop a social network that brings people together?
Achievements Currently, the projects is in its infancy, for the moment we have not achieved much.</description></item><item><title>Filebackup</title><link>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/filebackup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 08:15:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/filebackup/</guid><description>Subject My mom asked me for an app where she could store her sheet music and find it easily. So I proposed her to make it in order to train myself. The project is still in progress.
Problem How to save files in a secure way while making them accessible?
Achievements For the moment, the back-end part of the application (in python) has started, but the front-end has not yet started.</description></item><item><title>Storage and Big Data</title><link>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/bigdata/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 12:15:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/bigdata/</guid><description>Subject The enormous potential associated with medical data has led the healthcare industry to a significant and rapid transformation. As a result, the requirements for implementing improvements are becoming more and more significant. To move forward in the right direction, practitioners (physicians, nurses) and facility administrators need direct access to actionable information in medical data to improve performance and quality of care in measurable ways. The demand for actionable information from integrated medical data is growing.</description></item><item><title>System programming</title><link>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/sysprog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 12:15:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/sysprog/</guid><description>Subject Our team has just joined the software publisher ProSoft. We have to develop a backup software under the responsibility of the CIO. This backup software is part of the &amp;ldquo;EasySave&amp;rdquo; project, so it is our responsibility to manage this project.
Problem How to make multiple secure backups?
Achievements First of all, we had to create a console application offering several types of backups. Indeed, we had the choice between full backups (all files), and partial backups (only different files).</description></item><item><title>Information system</title><link>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/isystem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 12:15:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/isystem/</guid><description>Subject Having purchased the company ABSTERGO, ANIMUS is looking to integrate their their information system with their own.
Problem How to integrate ABSTERGO&amp;rsquo;s information system with that of ANIMUS while ensuring security?
Achievements We worked on the security of the information system of the company ABSTERGO which was bought by the company ANIMUS. This information system includes following equipment:
Two routers: One primary, one secondary, in order to have redundancy. Two firewalls: One primary, one secondary, in order to have redundancy.</description></item><item><title>Web development</title><link>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/webdev/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 12:15:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/webdev/</guid><description>Subject The objective of this project was to create a website gathering the different internship offers, and displaying the companies looking for or having an intern. It was possible to search for an offer, to modify, to add and to delete it. These were classified by skills in order to obtain a relevant search result.
Problem How can we create an intuitive site that will allow students to search for internships?</description></item><item><title>Network</title><link>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/network/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 12:15:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/network/</guid><description>Subject The mayor of Funkytown (a fictional city) wants to support a digital policy for the city&amp;rsquo;s businesses. This support comes at the right time for the ESN eXia, which has just set up in the city. Many contracts have been won thanks to this support policy.
Problem How to deploy configurations for all businesses in the city?
Achievements During this project we worked on a packet tracer model regrouping several companies or premises.</description></item><item><title>OOP</title><link>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/oop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 12:15:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/oop/</guid><description>Subject A new company selling electronic components online is looking to develop its information system. Thus, we will have to create an application that will allow the company to manage its business processes.
Problem How to realize a solution allowing a company to manage its business processes?
Achievements First of all, we were able to read and understand the specifications that were given to us. Thanks to the different information available in the project specifications, we were able to create a data dictionary.</description></item><item><title>Embedded system</title><link>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/embeddedsystem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 12:15:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/embeddedsystem/</guid><description>Subject The International Meteorological Agency (IMAA) has a project to deploy surveillance ships equipped with on-board weather stations. The purpose of weather stations is to measure the parameters influencing natural disasters. For this, they must be simple, efficient and controllable by a crew member.
Problem How to make a simple and effective weather station?
Achievements First of all, we had the following hardware:
An AVR ATmega328 microcontroller integrated to the Arduino board to design the prototype.</description></item><item><title>Industry</title><link>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/industry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 12:15:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/industry/</guid><description>Subject After 2 years of intense research and development, the young French start-up NOSE has succeeded in developing an innovative process for the detection and analysis of fine particles in the air. According to the arguments put forward by its creators, the NOSE technology will make it possible to manufacture air quality monitoring devices at a very low cost, which will enable this technology to be deployed on a very large scale.</description></item><item><title>Signal</title><link>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/signal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 12:15:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/signal/</guid><description>Subject Agent K17 has infiltrated the secret base of major web hackers and managed to steal information from them but unfortunately is stuck in a conference room. He must transmit the information and send the emergency code &amp;ldquo;ESCAPE K17&amp;rdquo; without being detected.
Problem How to pass a message that must be undetectable through a microphone used by a a third party?
Achievements We started by studying the sound in a general way, and deduced that all the frequencies were not audible by the Man, and that these frequencies leave a trace called spectrum which can be obtained from a sound signal.</description></item><item><title>Data Base</title><link>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/database/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 12:15:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/database/</guid><description>Subject Hephaestus makes legendary weapons and equipment, and with the help of Hermes, his business is flourishing. Hermes wanted to establish himself in Egypt and managed to take over the administration and management of Hephaestus&amp;rsquo; sales. He then wishes to exploit the data collected by Hephaestus during the last centuries in order to increase the sales.
Problem How can Hermès increase sales?
Achievements We started by creating an algebraic model. Indeed we had to go from a database realized on Excel, to a clean database with MySQL.</description></item><item><title>Electronics</title><link>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/electronics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 12:15:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://rakk0o.aphorya.fr/blogs/electronics/</guid><description>Subject The MI7 spy agency asked us to work on a new generation safe with increased authentication mechanisms. Thus, there would be several electronic cards with their own number. These cards could then activate the authentication system, which is composed of several authentication levels.
Problem How to make a card able to secure authentication?
Achievements We started by making a logigram corresponding to the different cards linked to a certain authentication level.</description></item></channel></rss>